Mohammad Ibrahim Israr

<u>israr.m.ibrahim@gmail.com</u> ♦ <u>linkedin.com/in/mohammad-israr</u> ♦ <u>ibrahimisrar.com</u> ♦ <u>github.com/ibrahi-m0h</u> ♦ (949) 439-0010

Career Objective

To utilize the knowledge and experience gained within my coursework and projects while acquiring my degree in Computer Science. I strive to learn the different areas of focus within the Technology domain and utilize the knowledge to enhance my abilities to grow within software engineering.

Education

California State University, Fullerton

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

achelor of Science in Computer Science Graduation Date: May 2024

Experience

Headstarter Al

Software Engineering Fellow

July 2024 - Sept. 2024

- Currently in the process of building 5 A.I. apps and API's using NextJS, OpenAI, and StripeAPI
- Developing projects from design to deployment in collaboration with 3 engineering fellows using MVC design patterns
- Collaboration with team using Agile and Scrum methodologies
- Receiving full-stack experience by using ReactJS, API's, and databases in all 5 applications

ACM, Association for Computing Machinery, California State University, Fullerton

February 2022- Aug 2022

Secretary

- Oversee emails being sent from tech companies like NVIDIA, Microsoft, and Amazon
- Communicate with members regarding educational and career opportunities offered by these tech companies
- Participated in workshops related to algorithms, web-design, and the Agile methodology

Muslim Youth Project, CA

Social Media Marketing Director

December 2021 - May 2024

- Ensure relevant information and creative content is broadcasted to families across SoCal so that MYP can further it's positive impact in the SoCal community
- Graphic Design, Project Management, Canva, Cross-functional Team Leadership, Public Speaking, Market Research, Brand Development, and MailChimp

SoCal MIST. CA

Webmaster

October 2022 - May 2023

- Responsible for keeping SoCal MIST's website updated and relevant
- Optimizing the website to be viewed from multiple viewing platforms
- Created wireframe mockups to be approved by team before implementation of features
- Website bootstrapping using Create React App

Salaam Corner | OCIF, Mission Viejo, CA

Committee Chair

March 2021 – December 2022

- Leading a team of like-minded individuals with strategic planning for events
- · Programming weekly meeting agendas
- Annual Budget Planning
- Public Speaking
- Community engagement with other organizations

Staples, Inc.

Technology Associate

December 2018 - August 2020

- Demonstrated extensive knowledge in technology including all hardware, software, and applications.
- Evaluated customer needs and provided a variety of service options and product options to meet their needs
- Effectively communicated with customers, peers, and leadership to help drive business

Skills

Programming: Python, JavaScript, React, NextJS, SQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS

Development Tools/IDE: Balsamiq Wireframes, Figma, Adobe XD, Arduino, Visual Studio Code, Virtual Box, Atom, Command Line,

Github

Relevant Coursework: Google UX Design, Data Structures, Algorithms, Front-End Engineering, Python & C++ Programming,

Introduction to Cyber Security, Software Engineering, File Structures, & iOS Development

Leadership Skills: Public Speaking, Event Planning, Project Management, Root-Cause Analysis

Projects

Weather Application Worked with a team to create a weather application using Kotlin. Played a key role regarding the creation of

UML diagrams and implementation. Several features implemented including push notifications, which can be

sent to user's phone depending on weather in user's location.

SoCal MIST Website Maintaining and updating a website that was built using React and is currently hosted using Firebase by

Google.

Pantry Tracker Created a full-stack inventory management system using NextJS, ReactJS, and Firebase, which allows user to

add, increment, decrement, or remove items from their inventory.